<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Akhil Peddikuppa</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Akhil Peddikuppa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shop Your Store</title>
      <link>/projects/shopyourstore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/shopyourstore/</guid>
      <description>An Android and iOS ecommerce app that gives every user their own &amp;ldquo;store&amp;rdquo;, so they can sell their items and &amp;ldquo;shop their store&amp;rdquo;.
  This project is geared at people who want to sell off old clothes and those you don&amp;rsquo;t have the means to run their own website due to cost.
  This app was built with the Flutter SDK as the front end and Cloud Firestore as the backend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internshift</title>
      <link>/projects/internshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/internshift/</guid>
      <description>App to aggregate internships and job openings for high school and college age students designed to decrease difficulty in the application process.
  Internships and jobs at an early age have been shown to increase a student&amp;rsquo;s success in their designated field.
  Built using Flutter SDK with Firebase Authentication for the authentication and Cloud Firestore for the Backend.
  Submitted to Congressional App Challenge under District TX-30 represented by Congresswoman Eddie Bernice Johnson and placed 2nd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BuzzerBowl</title>
      <link>/projects/buzzerbowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/buzzerbowl/</guid>
      <description>  An app for quizbowl players to practice quiz bowl questions
  Functionality includes ability to create or join games, practice, live buzzing, and native text-to-speech functionality for iOS, Android, MacOS, and Web.
  Front end made using the Flutter SDK and backend made using Cloud Firestore
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CommonPlace</title>
      <link>/projects/commonplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/commonplace/</guid>
      <description>  An app to connect the community in a neighborhood together.
  Features include direct messaging, user search, chat rooms, and secure sign in and sign up through Firebase Authentication
  Built using the Flutter SDK as a frontend and Cloud Firestore as a backend for chatrooms and user data storage
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porsche Taycan Edit Video</title>
      <link>/projects/porschetaycanvideo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/porschetaycanvideo/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>/projects/firstproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/firstproject/</guid>
      <description>This portfolio page was made using Hugo, a static site generator. I made this portfolio to showcase my resume, my projects, and some of thoughts in a blog format.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
